Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. To start off this unit, before
progressivism in US history, there will
be a very brief era of imperialism.
Imperialism here will simply mean that
the US will go out and try to take other
land and as a result become a world
global power. We already talked about
little examples like Hawaii and we'll
get to the big example next topic. For
now, we need to talk about debates over
imperialism because you have the side of
people who supported imperialism and the
side who didn't. This will be all we
cover this topic. So, let's try to go
through this debate as fast as we can.
Imperialists or those who support
imperialism will have mostly four
arguments. One, economics because
imperializing will lead to new markets
and resources. Two, power politics
because Europe was colonizing and the US
didn't want to fall behind. Three,
racism/ a quote civilizing mission
because of the belief that white
Anglo-Saxon Protestants or Wasps should
quote uplift others. And finally, four,
the frontier was closed. This idea was
caused by the 1890 census signaling
westward expansion was basically over.
Examples of people in this group are
Alfreder Mahan and Josiah Strong. Moving
on to the anti-imperialists. They will
have three arguments. One,
self-determination, meaning the idea of
being an empire contradicts US
Republican ideals and the literal
Declaration of Independence. Two is
racism because people on this side
didn't really want non-white people
added to the US. And finally, three,
isolationism. They argued Americans
should keep their focus at home and
avoid overseas entanglements. A group to
reference here might be the
Anti-Imperialist League. And a few
people to note might be Andrew Carnegie
and Mark Twain. I told you that was it.
On the screen now are AP style questions
for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.